Newland/Zeuner Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Vocal Music (Box 24-46, Box 56)
  - Secular vocal music (Box 41-46, Box 56)
    - Music for 1 voice - Printed music (Box 41-42, Box 56)
      - By Composer (Box 41-42)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - Die Hochzeit des Figaro, Includes: Air de Figaro. Mon enfant plus de tendres fleurettes (Non più andrai) Musique de Mozart, Chanté par Pellegrini. Paris: Pacini. Pl. no. (537). Aria - No. 25. (Il caproe la capretta). Bonn: N. Simrock. Pl. no. 28. Aria - No. 26. (In quell anni). Bonn: N. Simrock. Pl. no. 28. Arie. Non so più cosa son, cosa faccio (Neue Freuden neue Schmerzen) Musik von W. A. Mozart. Clavier-Auszug. Hamburg: J. A. Böhme. Vergiss mein nicht. Am Klavier. In Musik gesezt von W. A. Mozard[!]. Mainz: B. Schott. Pl. no. 26. (Box 41)
          - Die Zauberflöte, Includes: Arie - (In diesen heil'gen Hallen Kennt Man die Rache nicht). Für Klavier von Herrn Mozart. Wien: Artaria & Compl. Pl. no. 95. (Box 41)
        - Müller, Wenzel
          - Das neu Sontags Kind. Aria. Wer niemals einen Rausch hat g'habt, für das Clavier von Herrn Müller. Wien: Artaria Compl., n.d., Pl. no. 123. (Box 41)
        - Päer, Ferdinando
          - Camilla. Aria - (In 'quel gentil sembiante). [Bonn]: [N. Simrock], [1799]., Pl. no. 94. (Box 42)
          - Sargino. Recit. und Cavatina. Ach Sophie, süsses Leben, ja ich athme nur für dich (Ah Soffie mio caro bene) von Ferd. Pär. Hamburg: J. A. Böhme, n.d. (Box 42)
        - Paisiello, Giovanni
          - The Heiress. For Tenderness Form'd, a favorite song in the Heiress composed by Paesiello. [London]: W. Gawler, [ca. 1800]. (Box 42)
        - R. D.
          - The Irresolute Lover. The Words and Music by R. D. Esq. [London]: J. F-m, [1775?]., Printed songs - English (Box 42)
        - Rauzzini, Venanzio
          - The Battle of Maida. Recitative & Song composed by Mr. Rauzzini, Words by Sir George Dallas. London: Goulding, Phipps, D'Almaine & Co., [ca. 1804]. (Box 42)
        - Reeve, William
          - In the Purse, or Benevolent Tar. The Galley Slave. Composed by Mr. Reeve. London: Preston & Son, n.d. (Box 42)
        - Sessi, Marianne
          - Canzonetta composta da Signora Marianne Sessi. (Nasce nel vago aprile porporea Rosa... ) (Box 42)
        - Smith, Theodore
          - Rondo. The Words by a Young Gentleman. Set by Theodore Smith. London: Longman & Broderip, [1780?]. (Box 42)
        - Süssmayr, Franz Xaver
          - Der Spiegel von Arkadien. Gesänge für das Clavier von Herrn Süssmayr. Nro. 13. (Seit ich so viele Weiber fah) Heilbronn: J. Amon, n.d., Pl. no. 8 and/or 102 (Box 42)
        - Van Uffel, Jean
          - L'Arbre de Noël. Melodie de Jean van Uffel. (Composée en 1583) Paroles de Mr. Ed. Thierry. Musique arrangée par Albert Grisar. Paris: A. Meissonnier et Heugel, n.d., Pl. no. M.H. 446. (Box 42)
        - Weigl, Joseph
          - Aria. Je öfter ich es überlege etc. von Herrn Weigl. Heilbronn: J. Amon, n.d., Pl. no. 257. (Box 42)
        - Winter, Peter
          - Dem unterbrochen Opferfest. Aria von Hr. Capellmeister Winter. Nro. 7. (Ich war wann ich erwachte) Heilbronn: Amon & Compagnie, n.d., Pl. no. 169. (Box 42)
        - Zeuner, Charles
          - Blow, blow, blow, thou winter wind see: Music of Charles Zeuner: Secular vocal music, BOX: 55
      - Title only (Box 42, Box 56)
        - Advice to the Fair. Sung by Mrs. Wrighten at Vauxhall. Set by Mr. Hook. [London]: [s.n.], n.d., Printed songs - English (Box 42)
        - The Braes of Yarrow. Sung by Miss Thornton. [London]: S. A. P. T[hompson], n.d., Printed songs - English (Box 42)
        - The Larks Shrill Notes. Sung by Mrs. Vincent at Vauxhall., Pl. no. 6.; Printed songs - English (Box 42)
        - Rosline Castle., Printed songs - English (Box 42)
        - The Soger Lassie. Sung by Miss Thornton., Pl. no. 54.; Printed songs - English (Box 42)
        - Spring the Soul Firing. A favorite Song in the Spanish Barber. No. 26. London: Longman & Briderip, n.d., Printed songs - English (Box 42)
        - The Wandering Sailor. Sung by Mr. Bannister in the Summer Amusement. [London]: S. A. P. T[hompson], n.d., Printed songs - English (Box 42)
        - Lied eines betrübten Mädchens an die Tugend [and] Alles, nur nicht die Ruhe [and] Ist sie von Adel? No. 6-8., Printed songs - German (Box 42)
        - Lieder der Schweizerischen Musikgesellschaft bey Ihrer 17n Versammlung in Zürich. 1829., Printed songs - German; [on verso] Bewillkommungslied (Seyt uns zum viertenmal villkommen) (Box 42)
        - Trauerlied auf Ludwig den sechszehnten. Verfasst und in Musik gesetzt von Roman Schad. Coburg: Commission des Meuselischen Leseinstituts, 1794., Printed songs - German (Box 56)
        - Dänische [und] Schwedische Nationallieder aus der Sammlung, die gegen 90 Melodien enthält. (Beylage zur allgemeinen musikalischen Zeitung. No. 6, 7)., Printed songs - Scandinavian (Box 42)
    - Music for 1 voice - Manuscripts (Box 42-43)
      - By Composer (Box 42-43)
        - Beethoven, Ludwig van
          - Knowest thou the land [Op. 75, no.1] (Box 42)
        - Blangini, F.
          - [Song] see: Paer, Romance, Box 42
        - Castelli
          - [Song] see: Paer, Romance, Box 42
        - Hoffmann, H. A.
          - Air (Box 42)
        - Meignen, Leopold
          - L'Attente (Box 42)
        - Mosca, Luigi
          - Cavatina (Box 42)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - Die Entführung aus dem Serail. Aria (Box 42)
          - Arias, Arias copied by Charles Zeuner from: Abendempfindung Don Giovanni Die Entführung aus dem Serail Die Zauberflöte (Box 42)
        - Muzzini
          - Senti il mio Coro. Sammlung verschiedener Gesänge mit Begleitung des Klavier's. M. Resch. (Box 42)
        - Naderman, François Joseph
          - [Song] see: Paer, Romance, Box 42
        - Päer, Ferdinando
          - Achille. Aria (Box 42)
          - Romance, also includes: secular songs for one voice by Blangini, Castelli, Naderman, and Romagnesi (Box 42)
          - Arias, copied by Charles Zeuner (Box 42)
        - Romagnesi
          - [Song] see: Paer, Romance, Box 42
        - Rossini, Gioacchino
          - Il Barbiera di Siviglia - Cavatina (Box 43)
        - Unilau
          - 2 Romanzen aus der Oprette Das Irrlicht., Arranged by [?].anicher (Box 43)
        - Weber, Carl Maria von
          - Der Freischütz. Aria (Box 43)
        - Zelter, Carl Friedrich
          - Feenreigen aus Schillers Musen-Almanach 1798 (Box 43)
        - Zingarelli, Nicolo
          - Lucido eccelso Nume (Box 43)
        - Zumsteeg, Johann Rudolf
          - An die Menschengelichter, Title page reads: Zumsteg (Box 43)
          - Canzonette (Box 43)
      - Title only (Box 43)
        - [Songs - English] (Box 43)
        - [Songs - German] (Box 43)
        - [Songs - German - Books (2)] (Box 43)
        - [Songs - German - Compilation] (Box 43)
        - [Songs - German - Guitar accomp.] (Box 43)
        - [Miscellaneous song fragments] (Box 43)
        - [Miscellaneous song title pages] (Box 43)
    - Music for 2 or more voices - Printed music (Box 44-45, Box 56)
      - By Composer (Box 44-45, Box 56)
        - Campana, Fabio
          - Dimmi che m'ami! Duettino. Musica del M. Campana., Pl. no. G, A & Co. 726. (Box 44)
        - Clapisson, Louis
          - Le Coffret de St. Domingue. Opéra comique en un acte. Paroles de Mr Emile Deschamps. Paris: Magasin des Demoiselles, 1854-1855. (Box 44)
        - Dietsch, Pierre-Louis-Philippe
          - Mois de Marie. 20 Motets à une, deux et trois Voix égales avec Acc. d'Orgue ou d'Harmonium ou de Piano par L. Dietsch. Paris: S. Richault, n.d., Pl. no. 9849.R. (Box 44)
        - Dittersdorf, Karl
          - Aus dem rothen Käppchen, Includes: Aria - No. 5. (Lustig leben die Soldaten). Pl. no. 161. Duetto - No. 15. (Ach liebes Hänschen fey so gut) Pl. no. 161. (Box 44)
        - Gluck, Christoph Willibald
          - Iphigénie en Aulide=Iphigenia in Aulis, Tragédie lyrique en trois actes=Lyrische Tragödie in drie Aufzügen, Mise en musique par Mr. le chevalier Gluck=In Musik gesetzt von dem Ritter Gluck. Arrangée pour le Pianoforte von J. D. Sander. Erster Act. Berlin: Sanders Buchhandlung, [1808?]. (Box 56)
        - Henrion, Paul
          - La Treille du roi. Opéra-comique en un acte. Paroles de M. Charles Depeuty. Paris: Magasin des Demoiselles, 1856-1857. (Box 44)
        - Himmel, Friedrich Heinrich
          - Fanchon das Leyermädchen, nach dem französischen Vaudeville bearbeitet von A. v. Kotzebue, in Musik gesetzt von Friederich Heinrich Himmel. Clavier Auszug. Amsterdam: A. Kuntze, [180-]., Pl. no. 18. (Box 44)
        - Johnson, Ben
          - Drink to me only. A favorite Glee for three Voices with the Original Words by Ben Johnson. [London]: T. Straight, n.d. (Box 44)
        - Lampugnani, Giovanni Baptista
          - Quintetto. No. 4. (Il villan che colti vail giardino), from L'amor contadine by Lampugnani?; Pl. no. 13. (Box 44)
        - Massé, Victor
          - Le Prix de famille. Opéra Comique en un acte. Paroles de Méry. Paris: Magasin des Demoiselles, 1855-1856. (Box 44)
        - Meyerbeer, Giacomo
          - Aus Margherita d'Anjou von Meyer-Beer. (No. I. Beilage zur allgem. musikalischen Zeitung. 1821. No. 2). (Box 44)
        - Miller, Julius
          - Sechs Canons komischen Inhalts für drei Singstimmen ohne Begleitung componirt von Julius Miller. 2s Werk. Leipzig: Friedr. Hofmeister, [before 1815]., Pl. no. 175. (Box 45)
        - Möller, N.
          - Tio Sånger ur Lucksalighetens Ö satta i Musik och tillegnade Författaren af N. Möller. Stockholm: C. Müller, n.d. (Box 45)
        - Moore, Thomas
          - Oh Lady Fair! A Ballad for Three Voices. [London]: James Carpenter, 1802. (Box 45)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - Die Zauberflöte. Duet - Bei Männern welche Liebe Fühlen. Für das Klavier aus der Opera Die Zauberflöte von Herrn Mozart. Wien: Artaria u. Compl., n.d., Pl. no. 94 (Box 45)
        - Purcell, Henry
          - Britons Strike Home, a favorite duett composed by Purcel[!]. Arranged for the Piano Forte. London: G. Shade, n.d. (Box 45)
        - Root, George F.
          - The Flower Queen, or the Coronation of the Rose. A Cantata in two parts, for the use of singing classes in academies, female seminaries & high schools, adapted especially for concerts, anniversaries, or other festive occasions, and also for the social circle. Poetry by Miss Frances Jane Crosby. Music composed by Geo. F. Root. New York: Mason Brothers, n.d. (Box 45)
        - Stevenson, John Andrew
          - See our oars with feathered spray see: Mozart, Twelfth Mass, Box 24
        - Winter, Peter
          - Das Unterbrochene Opferfest. Quartetto. No. 18. (Kind! willst du ruhig schlafen), Pl. no. 61. (Box 45)
      - Title only (Box 45)
        - Apollo Sammlung auserlesener Gesangstücke aus Opern, Concerten, Oratorien, etc., alter und neuer Zeit. Braunschweig: F. Busse, [183-]. (Box 45)
        - Cruel Flatterer - The admired Duet Sung by Miss Abrahams and Miss Field in the Critic. Adapted for the Harpsichord, with English & Italian Words. [London]: L & B, n.d. (Box 45)
        - [Unidentified], SATB arr.; [O Brignal banks are fresh and fair... ] (Box 45)
        - Vous l'ordonnez - To be Sung either as an Air, Duett or Trio [by Monsigny?]. [S.l.]: Babb, [1800?]. (Box 45)
        - [Excerpt from book of duets and glees], Includes: Our Way Across the Sea - Duet. May-Day Song - Solo and Duet from Haydn's The Seasons. My Native Land - Duet. Rise, Cynthia, Rise! - Glee [by] Hook. The Land of the Blest. (Box 45)
    - Music for 2 or more voices - Manuscripts (Box 45-46)
      - By Composer (Box 45-46)
        - Cherubini, Luigi
          - Opening Round., Adapted by T. Cooke (Box 45)
        - Handel, George Frideric
          - Patriotic Chorus (Box 45)
        - Hiller, Friedrich Adam
          - Hymne an die Tonkunst (Box 45)
        - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
          - [La Clemenza di Tito]. Duet (Box 45)
        - Newland, William Augustine
          - For our National Celebration July 4th (Box 45)
        - Rossini, Gioacchino
          - Otello. Duetto (Box 45)
        - Shaw, Oliver
          - There is an hour of peaceful rest (Box 45)
        - Warnitzky
          - Horcht, Vater, horcht (Box 46)
        - Weber, Carl Maria von
          - Der Freischütz. Terzett con Chor (Box 46)
      - Title only (Box 46)
        - The African's Complaint, Copied by Charles Zeuner (Box 46)
        - Hunters Glee (Box 46)
        - Oh! Then We Live! (Box 46)
        - When music swells (Box 46)
        - [Compilation of glees - hard cover] (Box 46)
        - [Four English songs for chorus] (Box 46)
        - [Unidentified German work for chorus and orchestra] (Box 46)
- Instruction and Study Materials (Box 47, Box 56)
  - Printed music (Box 47, Box 56)
    - By Composer (Box 47, Box 56)
      - Clifton, Arthur
        - Clifton's Piano-forte Preceptor, containing the Rudiments of Music, Exercises & Rules for Fingering and the Major & Minor Scales, together with a selection of Popular Airs & Lessons, Adapted by the Author. Third Edition. Baltimore: John Cole, 1839., Title page only (Box 47)
      - Holloway, John T. (arranger)
        - Singing School Exercises; designed to assist the teacher and aid pupils in singing schools in acquiring a practical knowledge of the principles of vocal music. Arranged by John T. Hollaway. Philadelphia: John T. Holloway, 1843., 2 copies (Box 47)
      - Horn, Henry
        - Rudiments for the single and double movement harp. Exemplified in a clear & concise manner with forty-two exercises for forming the hands and the fingering marked (to which are subjoined) forty-two progressive lessons constructed on pleasing familiar airs arranged in the principle keys, with the fingering marked where necessary, by Henry Horn. London: Goulding & D'Almaine, n.d., Title page only (Box 47)
      - Marpurg, Friedrich Wilhelm
        - Abhandlung von der Fuge - Exempel (Box 56)
      - Meignen, Leopold
        - L. Meignen's Elements of Vocal Music. (Box 47)
      - Mompour, F. J.
        - Der allgemeinen Harmonielehre, für angehende Tonkünstler mit ausführlichen Beijspielen, zum Selbstunterrichte, erläutert von F. J. Mompour. Frankfurt a/M: Fr. Ph. Dunst, [1830]., Pl. no. 3. (Box 47)
      - Zeckwer, Richard
        - Writing Book for Harmony Pupils. Edited for the use of the pupils of the Philadelphia Music Academy by Rich. Zeckwer. [S.l.]: [s.n.], 1885., [signed] Agnes Ethel Poulterer.; 2 copies (Box 47)
    - Title only (Box 47)
      - Elementary Principles of Music, Exercises of keys, intervals, rhythms, etc. (Box 47)
      - [Unidentified], Two books of instructions and practice pieces for the pianoforte; no title pages (Box 47)
      - Generalbass., [signed on cover] Carl Schulz (Box 47)
      - General=Bass. Exemel. in C clef and F clef (Box 47)
      - [Miscellaneous instructional pieces] (Box 47)
      - [Spanish lessons] (Box 47)
      - [Vocalization exercises] (Box 47)
- Music of Charles Zeuner (Box 48-57)
  - Music for solo instruments (Box 48-50, Box 57)
    - Organ (Box 48, Box 57)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Holographs (Box 48, Box 57)
        - Adagio[s] für die Orgel (Box 48)
        - Ausgeführten Choral (Box 48)
        - Largo für die Orgel see: Adagio
        - Fantasia [in G] (Box 48)
        - Fantasia for the organ (Box 48)
        - [Unidentified], 22 fantasias and fugues for the organ, nos. 3-22; for nos. 1-2, Box 57 (Box 48)
        - Fuga für die Orgel (Box 48)
        - Great fantasia (Box 48)
        - Organ fantasia (Box 48)
        - Organ fantasia and Capriccio (Box 48)
        - Polonaises, 2 hands (Box 48)
        - Polonaises, 4 hands (Box 48)
        - [Unidentified], Four fugues for the organ (Box 57)
        - [Unidentified], Fugue (Box 57)
        - [Unidentified], Organ prelude (Box 57)
        - [Unidentified], Organ Voluntaries, Part I (Box 48)
        - [Unidentified], Variations for organ on Handel's See the conquering hero come (Box 48)
        - [Miscellaneous organ chorales] (Box 48)
        - [Miscellaneous organ voluntaries] (Box 48)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Printed music (Box 48)
        - Zeuner's Organ Voluntaries in two parts. Boston: Parker & Ditson, 1840., Includes: Part I. 165 Interludes and Short Preludes in which are introduced all the Various Keys used in Modern Church Music. Part II. Practical Voluntaries to be used before and after Serivce in Churches. By Ch. Zeuner. Boston: Parker & Ditson. [Part II only] (Box 48)
    - Piano (Box 49, Box 57)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Holographs (Box 49, Box 57)
        - Boston Galopade (Box 57)
        - Fugues (Box 49)
        - Gallops (Box 49)
        - Introduction and Variations to Hail Columbia (Box 49)
        - Marches (Box 49)
        - Quicksteps (Box 49)
        - Rondos [and] Rondinos (Box 49)
        - VI Variationen für das Pianoforte (Box 49)
        - Spanish Dance No. 4 (Box 57)
        - Themes and Variations (Box 49)
        - Variations on the American National Song: Yankee Doodle (Box 49)
        - Waltzes (Box 49)
        - [Miscellaneous piano pieces] (Box 49)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Printed music (Box 49)
        - Eissler Quadrilles. Adapted by Francis Weiland, arranged for the Piano Forte by C. Zeuner. Philadelphia: Geo. W. Hewitt & Co., 1840. (Box 49)
        - 2nd Set of Tremont Quadrilles selected from Celebrated Operas, performed by Kendall & Sanborn's Band, arranged for the Piano Forte by Charles Zeuner. Boston: Henry Prentiss, n.d. (Box 49)
        - Three Divertisments for the Piano Forte [on] subjects from Norma by Ch. Zeuner. Philadelphia: John F. Nunns, 1841., Includes: No. 1. Ah Bello Ame Ritorna. (Box 49)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Manuscript copies in other hands (Box 49)
        - Fantasia and Polacca (Box 49)
        - President Harrison's Funeral March (Box 49)
        - Sonata (Box 49)
    - Violin (Box 50)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Holographs (Box 50)
        - Solo für Violino (Box 50)
        - zum Coda, fragment for solo violin (Box 50)
        - [Unidentified], violin and piano; Variations on Mozart's Là ci darem la mano (Box 50)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Manuscript copies in other hands (Box 28)
        - St John the Baptist see: Mozart, Mass No. 12, Box 28
    - Flute (Box 50, Box 57)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Holographs (Box 57)
        - Bagatellen für die Flöte, Variations for flute (Box 57)
      - Zeuner as Arranger (Box 50)
        - [Unidentified], flute or violin accompaniment to operatic overtures (Box 50)
  - Orchestral music (Box 50-51, Box 57)
    - Concertos and other concert works (Box 50-51, Box 57)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Holographs (Box 50-51, Box 57)
        - American Pot Pourri (pour le Cor) (Box 50)
        - Chor - Allegro (Box 50)
        - Clarinet Solo with Orchestra (Box 50)
        - Concerto [in C], V.2 and Vc. only (Box 57)
        - Fantasia, clarinet and timpani parts (Box 50)
        - [Unidentified], Oboe concerto (Box 50)
        - Organ Concerto [No. 1] (Box 50)
        - Organ Concerto [No. 1], clarinet part (Box 50)
        - Organ Concerto (No. 2), full score (Box 50)
        - Pot Pourri für Posthorn (Box 50)
        - [Unidentified], Variations in A Major for piano and orchestra (Box 51)
        - Variations on [Home] Sweet Home (Box 51)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Manuscript copies in other hands (Box 51)
        - First Organ Concerto (Box 51)
        - Second Grand Concerto for the Organ, orchestral parts (Box 51)
        - Two Organ Concertos, Nos. I & II., Arranged by W. A. Newland (Box 51)
    - Popular dance forms (Box 51, Box 57)
      - Zeuner as Composer: Holographs (Box 51, Box 57)
        - Allemande (Box 51)
        - Governor Everett's Quickstep (Box 51)
        - Military March, full Band (Box 57)
        - Masonic March (Box 51)
        - Rondo Polacca pour le Cor in Es (Box 51)
        - Rondo Polacca, for horn in F and orchestra (Box 51)
        - Quicksteps (Box 57)
        - [Unidentified], Work for band, dedicated to the Springfield MA Musical Society (Box 51)
        - [Miscellaneous dance music - keyboard] (Box 57)
      - Zeuner as Arranger (Box 51)
        - Washington's March (Box 51)
  - Sacred vocal music (Box 51-55, Box 57)
    - Zeuner as Composer: Holographs (Box 51-52, Box 57)
      - Benedictus (Box 51)
      - Cantata for 4 voices (Box 51)
      - Organ accompaniment by William Newland (Box 51)
      - Cavatina Basso, Agnus Dei (Box 57)
      - Gloria to a Jubilate Deo by B. Carr (Box 57)
      - Hope, our Support, score and parts (Box 51)
      - Hushed is the voice of Judah's mirth (Box 51)
      - The Lord unto my Lord thus spake (Box 52)
      - Missa (No. III in E-flat), orchestral score (Box 52)
      - Missa No. 3 in E-flat Organ accompaniment by William Newland, vocal score (Box 52)
      - O all ye nations praise the Lord, duet (Box 52)
      - O cease my wandering soul (Box 52)
      - O happy is the man (Box 52)
      - O praise God in his holiness (Box 52)
      - O praise ye the Lord (Box 52)
      - Parting hymn (Box 52)
      - Praise ye Jehovah's name, 2 copies (Box 52)
      - Praise Ye the Lord, fourth [of] July Cantata 1838 [in D] (Box 57)
      - Rejoice in the Lord O ye righteous (Box 52)
      - The swift declining day (Box 52)
      - Te Deum (Box 57)
      - There is an hour of peaceful rest (Box 52)
      - The Thunderstorm (Box 57)
      - [Compilation - sacred vocal] (Box 52)
      - [Service music - English] (Box 52)
      - [Miscellaneous sacred - English] (Box 52)
    - Zeuner as Composer: Printed music (Box 53)
      - The Feast of Tabernacles, an Oratorio, in two parts. Morning and Evening Sacrifice. The Words by Rev. Henry Ware, of Cambridge, the Music by Ch. Zeuner. [Boston]: Ch. Zeuner, 1837., Printed title pages pasted on books of copyist's music manuscript, with printed pages of music interspersed throughout (Box 53)
    - Zeuner as Composer: Manuscript copies in other hands (Box 53, Box 54)
      - The Feast of Tabernacles, vocal and instrumental parts (Box 53)
      - Make a joyful noise (Box 54)
      - Missa No. 3 in E-flat (Box 54)
      - O all ye Nations (Box 54)
      - O Salutaris hostia (from the 1st Organ Concerto, vocal melody by W. A. Newland) (Box 54)
      - Praise ye the Lord, orchestral accompaniment (Box 54)
      - Praise ye the Lord, keyboard accompaniment (Box 54)
      - There is an hour of peaceful rest (Box 54)
      - The Thunderstorm (Box 54)
      - We praise thee, O God (Box 54)
    - Zeuner as orchestrator (Box 54)
      - Jackson, William
        - Blow Ye the Trumpet on Zion (Box 54)
      - Jommelli, N.
        - Glory Be to God on High: Chorus & Fuga (Box 54)
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
        - Glory Be to God on High (Box 54)
        - O God! when thou appearst (Box 54)
      - Neukomm, Sigismund Ritter von
        - David, excerpts (Box 54)
      - Righini, Vincenzo
        - Behold & see the goodness of the Lord (Box 54)
    - Zeuner as Compiler (Box 55)
      - [Book of hymns] (Box 55)
  - Secular vocal music (Box 55, Box 57)
    - Zeuner as Composer: Holographs (Box 55, Box 57)
      - American Songs [and] American Glees (Box 55)
      - Away! Away! Bear me away!, Sonnet by Miss Kemble (Box 57)
      - The Bride's Farewell (Box 55)
      - Consiglio alla Gioventú (Box 55)
      - The Glasses Sparkling on the Bord, Glee for 4 male voices (Box 55)
      - Good Night (Box 57)
      - Let other nations proudly tell (Box 57)
      - Mrs. Adams Welcome to General Jackson (Box 55)
      - Sechs Lieder von Theodor Körner (Box 55)
      - These prairies glow with flowers (Box 55)
      - Wallhaide (Box 55)
      - Wiegenlied (Box 55)
      - Der Winter (Box 55)
      - [Miscellaneous Songs - German and English] (Box 55)
      - [Miscellaneous Part Songs - German and English] (Box 55)